large language models are very good
大型语言模型非常擅长
at transforming its input to a different format
把它的输入转换成不同的格式
such as inputting a piece of text in one language
比如用一种语言输入一段文字
and transforming it or translating it
对它进行变换或平移
to a different language
到另一种语言
or helping with spelling and grammar corrections
或者帮助纠正拼写和语法错误
so taking us in for the piece of tech
所以带我们去买个科技产品
that may not be fully grammatical
这可能不完全符合语法
and helping you to fix that up a bit
帮你解决这个问题
or even transforming formats such as inputting HTML
甚至转换格式，如输入HTML
and outputting JSN
输出JSN
so there's a bunch of applications that
有很多应用
I used to write
我曾经写过
somewhat painfully with a bunch of regular
和一群普通的
expressions that would
表达方式
definitely be
肯定是
much more
更
simply implemented now with a large language model
现在用一个大的语言模型简单地实现了
and a few prompts
还有一些提示
yeah I use charge GBT to proofread pretty much
是的，我经常用chatGBT来校对
everything I write these days
这些天我写的所有东西
so I'm excited to show you
所以我很高兴向你们展示
some more examples in the notebook now
笔记本上还有一些例子
so first we'll import Openai and also
首先我们导入Openai
use the same
使用相同的
Gat completion helper function that we've been using
我们一直在用的Gat补全辅助函数
throughout the videos
在整个视频中
and the first thing we'll do is a translation task
我们首先要做的是翻译任务
so large language models are trained on
所以大型的语言模型被训练
a lot of text from
很多文本来自
many sources a lot of which is the internet
很多资源，其中很多来自互联网
and this is
这是
kind of of course in many different languages
当然在很多不同的语言中都有
so this kind of imbues the model
这是模型的一部分
with the ability to do translation
具备一定的翻译能力
and these models know kind of hundreds of languages
这些模型知道几百种语言
to varying degrees of proficiency
熟练程度不同
and so we'll go through
我们会继续讲下去
some examples of how to use this capability
一些如何使用此功能的示例
so let's start off with something simple
让我们从简单的开始
so in this first example the prompt is
在第一个例子中，提示符是
translate the following English text to Spanish
把下面的英文文本翻译成西班牙语
hi I would like to order a blender
你好，我想订购一台搅拌机
and the response is ola mi gustaria or dena una liquid
反应是液态的或液态的
kuadora
kuadora
and I'm very sorry to all of you Spanish speakers
我对所有说西班牙语的人感到非常抱歉
I never Learned Spanish unfortunately
不幸的是，我从未学过西班牙语
as you can definitely tell
你肯定能看出来
okay let's try another example
好，我们再来举个例子
so
所以
in this example
在这个例子中
the prompt is tell me what language this is
提示是告诉我这是什么语言
and then this is in French combiancutlu lampedare
这是法语combiancutlu lampedare
and so let's run this
我们运行一下
and the model has identified that this is French
这个模型已经识别出这是法国的
the model can also do multiple translations at once
该模型还可以同时进行多个翻译
so in this example
在这个例子中
let's say
假设
translate the following text to French and Spanish
将以下文本翻译成法语和西班牙语
and you know what let's add another and English
你知道吗，我们再加一个和英语
pirate
海盗
and the text is I want to order a basketball
短信是我想订一个篮球
so here we have French
这是法语
Spanish and English pirates
西班牙和英国海盗
so in some languages
在某些语言中
the translation can change
翻译可以改变
depending on the speakers relationship to the listener
取决于说话者和听者的关系
and you can also explain this to the language model
你也可以把这个解释给语言模型
and so it will be able to
所以它能够
kind of translate accordingly
相应的翻译
so in this example we say
在这个例子中我们说
translate the following text to Spanish
把下面的文字翻译成西班牙语
in both the formal and informal forms
无论是正式的还是非正式的
would you like to order a pillow
您要订个枕头吗
and also notice here we're using a different delimiter
注意这里我们用了不同的分隔符
than these baptics
而不是这些洗礼
it doesn't really matter
这并不重要
as long as it's kind of a clear separation
只要有明确的界限就行
so here we have the formal and informal
这里我们有正式的和非正式的
so formal is when you're speaking to someone who's
所以正式是当你和某人说话时
maybe senior to you or you're in a
也许比你级别高，或者你在
professional situation
专业的情况
that's when you use a formal tone
这就是你使用正式语气的时候
and then informal is when you're speaking to
非正式的是当你和某人说话的时候
maybe a group of friends
也许是一群朋友
I don't actually speak Spanish but
我不会说西班牙语，不过
my dad does and he says that this is correct
我爸爸做了，他说这是正确的
so for the next example
下一个例子
we're going to pretend that we're in charge of a
假设我们负责一个
multinational e commerce company
跨国电子商务公司
and so the user messages are going to be
用户消息将会是
in all different languages
在所有不同的语言
and so users are going to be telling us about their it
所以用户会告诉我们他们的信息
issues in a wide variety of languages
各种语言的问题
so we need a universal translator
所以我们需要一个通用翻译器
so first we'll just paste in
首先我们粘贴进去
a list of user messages in
中的用户消息列表
a variety of different languages
各种不同的语言
and now we will loop through
现在我们循环一下
each of these
每一个
user messages so for issue in user messages
用户消息因此在用户消息的问题
and then I'm going to copy over
然后我要复制过来
this slightly longer code block
这个稍长的代码块
and so the first thing we'll do is ask the model to
所以我们要做的第一件事就是让模型
tell us what language the issue is in
告诉我们问题是用什么语言写的
so here's the prompt
这是提示符
then we'll print out the
然后打印出来
original messages language and the issue
原始信息的语言和问题
and then we'll ask the model to translate it into
然后我们让模型把它转换成
English and Korean
英语和韩语
so let's run this
我们运行一下
so the original message in French
这是法语原文
so we have variety of languages
所以我们有多种语言
and then the model translates
然后模型进行翻译
them into English and then Korean
把它们翻译成英语，然后是韩语
and you can kind of see here
你可以在这里看到
so the model says this is French
模型说这是法语
so that's because the
这是因为
response from this prompt is going to be this is French
这个提示符的响应将是this is French
you could try
你可以试试
editing this prompt to say something like
编辑这个提示，让它像
tell me what language this is respond with only one
告诉我这是什么语言，只回答一个
with only one word or don't use a sentence
只用一个词或者不要用一个句子
that kind of thing
诸如此类的事情
if you wanted this to just speak one word
如果你想让我说一句话
or you could
或者你可以
ask for it in a JSON format or something like that
请求JSON格式或类似的格式
which would probably encourage it to
这可能会鼓励它这么做
not use a whole sentence
不要用整个句子
and so amazing you've just built a universal translator
你造了一个通用翻译器真是太神奇了
and also feel free to pause the video
你也可以暂停视频
and add kind of any
然后加上任何
other language you want to try here
你想试试别的语言吗
maybe languages you speak yourself
也许是你自己会说的语言
and see how the model does
看看模型是怎样的
so the next thing we're going to
接下来我们要做的是
dive into is tone transformation
深入研究他的语气变化
writing can vary based on an intended audience
写作可以根据目标读者的不同而有所不同
you know the way that I would write an email to a
你知道我给a写电子邮件的方式
colleague or a professor is
同事或教授是
obviously going to be
显然会是
quite different to the way I text my younger brother
和我给我弟弟发短信的方式完全不同
and so Chuck
and so Chuck
GBT can actually also help produce different tones
GBT实际上也可以帮助产生不同的音调
so let's look at some examples
我们来看一些例子
so in this first example
在第一个例子中
the prompt is
提示符是
translate
翻译
the following from slang to a business letter
下面从俚语转到商务信函
dude this is Joe
伙计，这是乔
check out this spec on the standing lamp
看看立灯的规格
so
所以
execute this
执行这个
and as you can see
如你所见
we have a much more formal business letter
我们的商务信函要正式得多
with a proposal for a standing lamp specification
并提出了一项立灯规范的建议
the next thing that we're going to do is
接下来我们要做的是
to combert between different formats
在不同的格式之间进行转换
chart GBT
chart GBT
is very good at translating
擅长翻译吗
between different formats such as JSON to HTML
不同格式(如JSON到HTML)之间的转换
you know XML all kinds of things
你知道XML，所有的东西
Mark down
记下
and so in the prompt
所以在提示中
we'll describe both the input and the output formats
我们将描述输入和输出格式
so here is an example
这里有一个例子
so we have this
我们得到了这个
JSON that contains
JSON，包含
a list of restaurant employees with their name
一份餐馆员工名单，上面有他们的名字
and email
和电子邮件
and then in the prompt
然后在提示符中
we're going to
我们要
ask the model to translate this from JSON to HTML
要求模型将其从JSON转换为HTML
so the prompt is
提示符是
translate the following
翻译以下内容
Python dictionary from JSON to an
从JSON到an的Python字典
HTML table with column headers and titles
带有列头和标题的HTML表
and
和
then will
然后将
get the response
获取响应
from the model and print it
从模型中打印出来
so here we have some
这里有一些
HTML displaying all of the employee names and emails
显示所有员工姓名和电子邮件的HTML
and so now let's see if we can actually view this HTML
现在让我们看看能否查看这个HTML
so
所以
we're going to use this display function
我们将使用这个显示函数
from this Python library display HTML
从这个Python库显示HTML
response
响应
and here you can see that this is a properly formatted
这里你可以看到这是一个正确的格式
HTML table
HTML表
the next transformation task we're going to do
我们要做的下一个变换任务
is spell check and grammar checking
拼写检查和语法检查
and this is a really kind of popular use for ChatGPT
这是ChatGPT的一种非常流行的用法
I highly recommend doing this I do this all the time
我强烈建议你这么做，我一直都这么做
and this is
这是
especially useful when you're working in a non
当你在非营利性组织工作时尤其有用
native language
母语
and so here are some examples
这里有一些例子
of some common grammar and spelling problems and how
一些常见的语法和拼写问题和如何
the language model can help address these
语言模型可以帮助解决这些问题
so I'm going to paste in
我要粘贴进去
a list of
以下是
sentences that have some grammatical or spelling errors
有语法或拼写错误的句子
and then we're going to
然后我们要
loop through each of these sentences
循环遍历这些句子
and
和
ask the model to proofread these
请模特校对一下
proofread and correct
校对和更正
and then we'll use some dlimeters
然后我们用一些分尺
and then we will get the response and print it as usual
然后我们将得到响应并像往常一样打印它
and so the model is able to correct
这样模型就可以进行修正
all of these grammatical errors
所有这些语法错误
we could use
我们可以用
some of the techniques that we've discussed before
我们之前讨论过的一些技术
so
所以
we could to improve the prompt
我们可以改进提示
we could say pre read and correct
我们可以说预读和更正
the following text
下面的文字
and rewrite oh
重写哦
and rewrite the whole
重写整个
and rewrite it
重写一下
corrected
纠正
version if you
版本如果你
don't find
找不到
any errors
任何错误
just say
只是说
no errors found
没有发现错误
let's try this
我们来试试这个
so this way we were able to
这样我们就可以
oh they're still using quotes here
哦，这里还是用引号
but you can imagine you'd be able to find
但你可以想象你能找到
a way with a little bit of
一种有一点
iterative prompt development
迭代式提示开发
to
来
kind of find a prompt that works more reliably every
找到一个更可靠的提示符
single time
一次
and so now we'll do another example
现在我们再做一个例子
it's always useful to check your tax before
事先查一下你的税单总是有用的
you post it in a public forum
你把它发布在公共论坛上
and so we'll go through an example of checking a review
我们来看一个检查评论的例子
and so here is a review about a stuffed panda
这是一篇关于熊猫毛绒玩具的评论
and so we're going to
所以我们要
ask the model to proofread and correct the review
请模特校对并更正评论
great so we have this corrected version
很好，我们有了这个修正版本
and one cool thing we can do is
我们能做的一件很酷的事是
find the kind of differences between our
找出我们之间的区别
original review and the model's output
原始评审和模型的输出
so we're going to use this
所以我们要用这个
red lines Python package to do this
红线Python包来做这个
and to we're going to get the diff between the original
我们将得到原始的差值
text of our review and the model output
我们的审查文本和模型输出
and then display this
然后显示这个
and so here you can see the diff between
所以这里你可以看到两者的区别
the original review and the model output
原始评审和模型输出
and the kind of things that have been corrected
以及那些已经被纠正的事情
so the prompts that we use was
所以我们使用的提示是
proofread and correct this review
校对并修改这篇评论
but you can also make kind of more dramatic changes
但你也可以做出更大的改变
changes to tone
音调变化
that kind of thing
诸如此类的事情
so let's try
我们来试试
one more thing
还有一件事
so in this prompt
在这个提示中
we're going to
我们要
ask the model to proofread and correct
请模特校对和更正
this same review
同样的回顾
but also make it more compelling
但也让它更引人注目
and ensure that it follows APA style and
并确保它遵循APA格式
targets an advanced reader
针对高级读者
and we're also going to ask for the output
我们也会要求输出
and markdown format
和降价格式
and so we're using the same
所以我们用的是一样的
text from the original review
来自原始评论的文本
up here
在这里
so let's execute this
我们来执行这个
and here we have a
这里是a
expanded APA style review of the Soft Panda
扩大APA风格的软熊猫检讨
so this is it for the transforming video
这就是变换视频的内容
next up we have expanding where we'll take
接下来我们要扩展我们要去的地方
a shorter prompt and kind of generate a longer
一个较短的提示符会产生一个较长的提示符
more free form response from a language model
来自语言模型的更自由的形式响应